<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>a lazy blog</title>
    <description>a lazy blog
</description>
    <link>https://alazy.blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://alazy.blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 15:38:26 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 15:38:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.10.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Installing MySQL 5.7 Without Apt</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;steps-to-install-mysql-57-manually&quot;&gt;Steps to Install MySQL 5.7 Manually&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Download MySQL 5.7 Tarball&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Go to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.mysql.com/downloads/mysql/5.7.html&quot;&gt;MySQL Community Downloads&lt;/a&gt; page and download the correct tarball for your system.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Extract the Tarball&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Use the following command to extract the downloaded tarball:
```bash
tar -xvzf mysql-5.7.x-linux-glibc2.12-x86_64.tar.gz&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Move to desired directory&lt;/strong&gt;
Move the extracted MySQL folder to your desired directory (for example, /usr/local/mysql):
```bash
sudo mv mysql-5.7.x-linux-glibc2.12-x86_64 /usr/local/mysql&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create MySQL User and Group&lt;/strong&gt;
If the MySQL user and group don’t already exist, create them with the following commands:
```bash
sudo groupadd mysql
sudo useradd -r -g mysql -s /bin/false mysql&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Set Permissions for MySQL Directory&lt;/strong&gt;
Set the correct ownership of the MySQL directory:
```bash
sudo chown -R mysql:mysql /usr/local/mysql&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Initialize the MySQL Data Directory&lt;/strong&gt;
Go into the MySQL directory and initialize the data directory:
```bash
cd /usr/local/mysql
sudo ./bin/mysqld –initialize –user=mysql –datadir=/usr/local/mysql/data&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remove Old Symlink (If Applicable)&lt;/strong&gt;
If you have a newer version of MySQL installed (e.g., MySQL 8.0), remove the old symlink and create a new one:
```bash
sudo rm /usr/bin/mysql
sudo ln -s /usr/local/mysql/bin/mysql /usr/bin/mysql&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Verify&lt;/strong&gt;
```bash
mysql –version&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://alazy.blog/2025/02/mysql-5.7</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://alazy.blog/2025/02/mysql-5.7</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2024 YR4 Needs To Be Bigger</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-2024-yr4&quot;&gt;About 2024 YR4&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“2024 YR4” refers to an asteroid that was discovered relatively recently and is classified as a near-Earth object.
On Feb. 18, there was a 3.1% chance that 2024 YR4, estimated to be around 60 to 90 meters in diameter,
would impact Earth on Dec. 22, 2032, with a speed of 61,200 km/h.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given its size, a 60 to 90-meter asteroid would likely result in a localized explosion rather than a global extinction event.
The immediate area of impact would experience catastrophic effects, but the rest of the world will not face the same level of destruction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A one to 32 chance of collision, the highest Earth has seen in decades, and all the universe was able to summon up is 90 meters in diameter?
Climate change, air pollution, resource depletion, social inequality, political instability, global health issues. All problems that could have been solved,
but no, 90 meters it is. It needs to be bigger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-bigger&quot;&gt;Why Bigger?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, historically speaking, humanity has made great strides in emergency preparedness and disaster response.
In the wake of a catastrophic event, communities band together to rebuild and adapt.
We’ve seen this resilience after natural disasters; people come together to support one another.
We are clearly able to adapt to difficult situations, but what is the point? What is the end goal in this game?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s assume for a second we manage to stop buttfucking our future. We shift our focus to sustainability and make conscious choices that benefit both our planet and our communities.
But then, what does that future look like? What are we really aiming for? Harvesting black hole energy as a type 3 civilization?
Alright, what’s next then? Even if we discover all of the universe’s secrets, it’s going to end at some point, maximum entropy baby!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I say we need a shortcut, and a bigger asteroid might just be perfect. An event we have no control over, no responsibility.
We could “skip the cutscene” so to speak, and walk into extinction with dignity and acceptance.
Instead of clinging to the hope of fixing a broken system, what if we chose to embrace the final destination (pun intended) we all share?
This perspective offers a profound sense of liberation in acknowledging that all things have an end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I acquired this perspective on life when I was working 1st level support for my company.
By recognizing our impermanence, we can focus on living fully and meaningfully, making the most of the time we have left.
Or continue the same shit we’re doing, idk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://alazy.blog/2025/02/2024-YR4</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://alazy.blog/2025/02/2024-YR4</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Opsec - What, Why and How</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You’ve probably heard the phrase, “I have nothing to hide” at some point in your life. It’s a common response when people brush off concerns about privacy and security. But let’s be real—this mindset can be pretty risky in our digital age. That’s where Operational Security (OPSEC) comes in. It’s all about keeping your sensitive information safe from prying eyes. Let’s break down what OPSEC is, why it’s important, and how you can get started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-opsec&quot;&gt;What is OPSEC?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Operational Security, or OPSEC, is simply a fancy way of saying we need to protect our important information. It involves figuring out what you need to keep under wraps, understanding who might want to get their hands on it, and taking steps to keep it secure. OPSEC isn’t just for the military or big corporations; it’s something everyone should think about, especially when it comes to personal privacy and online safety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-should-you-care-about-opsec&quot;&gt;Why Should You Care About OPSEC?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether it’s your bank details, trade secrets, or personal stuff, losing control of your information can lead to some serious problems. No one wants that!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By knowing the potential threats out there, you can take steps to minimize them. It might mean tightening your online habits or beefing up your security measures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you run a business, showing that you care about OPSEC can go a long way in building trust with your customers. When people know their info is secure, they’re more likely to stick around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-get-started-with-opsec&quot;&gt;How to Get Started with OPSEC&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a good look at your current practices. Where could you be exposed? This could be anything from weak passwords to sharing too much online. Identifying these vulnerabilities is key to strengthening your defenses. I believe that the two key goals for maintaining effective OPSEC as a regular internet user are to limit information sharing and to utilize secure technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;1-limit-information-sharing&quot;&gt;1. Limit Information Sharing&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start by adopting a need-to-know mindset when you’re posting or sharing online. Before you share something personal on social media, ask yourself if it’s really necessary. For example, while it might seem harmless to post about your upcoming vacation, that information can signal to others that your home will be empty. Think about who will see your posts and whether that’s who you want knowing your personal business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, you can search for yourself online to see what information is publicly available. If you find any old posts or accounts that you no longer want out there, take the time to delete or update them. Also consider using a data removal service; there are countless online that will send requests on your behalf to have your personal information taken down from various websites and data brokers. You can find a list of services &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/10Vi38ZtHTyR0_LFEz-ON_RUH2ieT47z4/edit?pli=1&amp;amp;gid=1595621103#gid=1595621103&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;2-use-secure-technology&quot;&gt;2. Use Secure Technology&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;secure-messaging&quot;&gt;Secure Messaging&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to keeping your chats private, secure messaging apps are essential. Think of them as your digital fortresses, ensuring that your conversations stay confidential and are only visible to you and the people you trust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://signal.org/&quot;&gt;Signal&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://simplex.chat/&quot;&gt;SimpleX&lt;/a&gt; are some solid alternatives to WhatsApp if you’re willing to sacrifice some convenience for enhanced privacy and security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;virtual-private-networks-vpns&quot;&gt;Virtual Private Networks (VPNs)&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next on the list is using a VPN. This nifty tool encrypts your internet connection and hides your IP address, especially useful when you’re on public Wi-Fi. So, if you’re chilling at a café and want to browse without worrying about hackers, a VPN is your best friend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mullvad.net/&quot;&gt;Mullvad&lt;/a&gt; is a personal favorite of mine! Their servers never store any activity logs of any kind and payments can be done via cryptocurrencies like Monero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;secure-password-managers&quot;&gt;Secure Password Managers&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s face it: keeping track of passwords can be a nightmare. That’s where password managers like &lt;a href=&quot;https://keepassxc.org/&quot;&gt;KeePassXC&lt;/a&gt; come in. They store your passwords securely and even generate strong, unique ones for each of your accounts. Plus, many of them offer two-factor authentication (2FA), adding an extra layer of protection. It’s like having a personal security guard for your passwords!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;regular-software-updates&quot;&gt;Regular Software Updates&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t overlook the importance of keeping your software updated! Updates often fix security vulnerabilities that could be exploited by hackers. So, make it a habit to check for updates on your operating system and apps regularly to stay ahead of the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;identity-theft-protection-services&quot;&gt;Identity Theft Protection Services&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Identity theft protection services monitor your personal information online and let you know if they find it in places where it shouldn’t be—like the dark web. If something does go wrong, these services can help you recover your identity and guide you on how to keep your data safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, OPSEC isn’t a one-and-done deal. Regularly check in on your practices and stay updated on new threats. Doing routine checks and drills can help everyone remember their role in keeping things secure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://alazy.blog/2025/02/opsec</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://alazy.blog/2025/02/opsec</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
